Madalyn Breach

Web Developer | Salt Lake City | 541-213-1988 | madalynbreach@gmail.com

ABOUT ME

I created a custom major to specialize in computer policy as well as programming because I believe it is important to design programs that are ethical, safe, and accessible to **mitigate risk** and **develop** *better*. One of my best strengths I bring to a workplace is my positive attitude. Us computer folk need some fun once in a while, it helps to have **upbeat** people around that can still get the work done well.

EDUCATION

Westminster University, SLC (previously Westminster College)

Class of 2024

B.S. in Computer Science, Ethics and Policy | GPA:3.38 (Honors College Certificate)

Madras High School

3rd in Class | Honors Certificate | SkillsUSA Web Design 2nd in State | National History Day 1st in State

EXPERIENCE

Student Web Developer and Designer

Office of Marketing and Communications, Westminster University, SLC June 2020-Present

- Communicates in a timely manner, experienced in a remote work setting.
- Prioritizes tasks each morning in an **Agile**-adjacent manner, collaborating with supervisors to review, test, and debug material before publishing.
- Experience with CMS migration that required a thorough inspection and restructuring of both front end design and back end support.
- Manages form building and implementation via Formstack.
- Underwent a full site redesign. Turned given graphics into code.
- Constantly researching and learning new ways to develop.

Assistant Computer Science Teacher

Kearns High School (Title I), Kearns, UT Fall 2020-Spring 2022

 Assisted High School computer science teachers with little to no cs background with supplemental Exploring Computer Science curriculum tools, custom to the classroom and approachable to Title I students.

Teaching Assistant and Academic Tutor

Westminster University Computer Science Department, SLC Fall 2020-Fall 2021

- Hosted weekly help sessions, assisted in class by tracking lab partners, managed breakout rooms, Q&A, and facilitated the zoom chat into live discussion.

Caregiver with Adults Experiencing Disabilities

Opportunity Foundation Central Oregon

Summer 2018-On-Call Present

- Empowering 5 individuals by assisting them with every aspect of daily living including hygiene, transportation, eating, administering of medications, behavioral support and redirection, and communication.
- This job is the epitome of every soft skill in the book; I've never felt more challenged to be the best person I could be, every day, for the sake of my resident's quality of life. Because of the patience, care, and raw grit this job has required of me, I am fully confident in my ability to adapt, improve, and succeed at anything.

SKILLS

Programming:

HTML/CSS (Advanced) Javascript, React (Basic) Java (Proficient) Python (Basic) Agile

Platforms:

Slack, Asana, Adobe, OmniCampus, Sitefinity, Formstack, Spiceworks, Microsoft

PROJECTS

Personal Website:

HTML/CSS/JS site that displays animated sky.

React Notes App:

Post-it note board app built from a tutorial and debugged to fix spacing and element errors.

Utah Pride Center Check-In Web App:

Django app intended for kids to use to check in to their zoom meetings.

COMMUNITY ENGAGEMENT

Harvard WeCode Conference (zoom)

YWAM Digital Media Coordinator and Sound Technician